STAN NEO

Senior Data Scientist

(+65) 8606 8770

@ nhanwei@gmail.com

Singapore

in linkedin.com/in/nhanwei/

github.com/nhanwei
nhanwei.github.io

SUMMARY

Data Scientist with 7+ years of experience in using data to derive key insights and create business values. An analytics self-starter, I have initiated and executed numerous data science projects from ideation to delivery. In the past 3 years, I have also led and coached multiple junior data scientists to create data science solutions in an agile manner. In my next role, I aspire to become a better people leader who excels in both hands-on data science and project management. AWS certified.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SENIOR DATA SCIENTIST

Nov 2020—Present

Digital Bank in stealth mode - Singapore

25th employee of the new digital bank and answers directly to senior leadership

- Envision and execute bank-wide modelling and analytics roadmap
- Collaborate with product leaders to identify high impact opportunities
- Partner closely with engineering team to ensure best-in-class data science and MLOps practices using the AWS cloud
- Build segmentation models on partner data to support go-to-market strategies
- Lead **agile** ceremonies for team of analysts

FOUNDER Jun 2021—Present

Backdoorcode - Singapore

Subscription service for data science interviews that started from a pet project

 Built from scratch. Deployed backend services on a Raspberry Pi using a combination of Python, Gunicorn, Systemd, Cron, Stripe API Gateway, Webhooks, Lambda and S3

SENIOR DATA SCIENTIST

Mar 2019-Mar 2021

Metis – Singapore, San Francisco

- Led the Metis Data Science Bootcamp in Singapore as the Main Bootcamp Instructor and Senior Data Scientist.
- Coached junior data scientist and led daily stand-ups to ensure delivery of quality projects in an agile manner

DATA SCIENTIST

Jul 2018-Mar 2019

PALO IT – Singapore, Sydney

- **Deployed** an asynchronous **R model** on **MS Azure** using plumber, future, **docker** for a Reinsurance company in Australia.
- Built POCs on **Object Detection**, **Natural Language Processing** and **Sentiment Analysis**.

DATA SCIENTIST

Oct 2016-Jul 2018

DBS Bank – Singapore, Shanghai

• Responsible for building Machine Learning models for DBS Bank's regional markets: Singapore, Hong Kong and China.

KEY SKILLS

Python, PySpark, Keras, R
Pytorch, TensorFlow
Machine Learning, Deep
Learning
PostgreSQL, MongoDB
Hive, Hadoop, Mapreduce
AWS (EC2, S3, RDS, Lambda)
MS Azure
Docker and Kubernetes
Airflow, MLflow, W&B
Slack, Jira, Confluence
Bitbucket, Github
Tableau, Domo, Quicksight

EDUCATION

National University of Singapore

Master of Computing, Computer Science, 2019

National University of Singapore

Bachelor of Science (Hons), Statistics, 2015

- Second Upper
- Won 1st Prize in an R programming competition open to all Singapore universities undergraduates.
- Co-wrote an R package on the Hamiltonian Monte Carlo method for Final Year Project (See elhmc).

- Built a **product recommendation system** using the Wide-and-Deep model in Singapore using **Keras, TensorFlow** and **Python**.
- Developed the User-Based Collaborative Filtering Recommender System in China using R.
- Built models that attained at least 4X uplift for **multiple cross-sell**, **up-sell** and **acquisition** projects across numerous products using **R** and **Python**.
- Created a Machine Learning pipeline in R using H2O and R Shiny. Used by other co-workers.
- Mentored fresh hires in building Machine Learning models.

June 2015—Sep 2016

StarHub

DATA ANALYST

- Mined terabytes of raw, unstructured and structured telecommunication data using **Apache Spark**, **Pig**, **R** and **Python**.
- Developed geo-location algorithms to uncover subscribers' travelling and websurfing behaviors.

The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology

Summer Student Exchange Program 2014

Other Activities

Cloud Certifications

• AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner (Feb 2020)

MOOCs 2014—Present

- Completed 39 MOOC courses (as of Jan 2022) that are related to Data Science.
- Completed 5 DeepLearning. Al specialisations (MLOps, DL, NLP, GANs and TensorFlow Developer).
- Completed Google Analytics for Beginners and Advanced Google Analytics by Google

Kaggle

• Top 8% for Walmart Recruitment Competition (78th/1047)

Agile Fundamentals

• ICAgile Certified Professional (Jan 2019)

MISCELLANEOUS INFORMATION

Languages

Native Proficiency in English and Mandarin (Oral and Written)